<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Have a rad summer</title>
    <description>This is our travelblog Hope you like it
</description>
    <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.havearadsummer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 16:39:45 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 16:39:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day 1 - Nice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nice/nice.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
It’s a good thing people stay out late here cause we are sleeping right on through this day.  We arrived in Nice late last night and while Jeremy and I were ready to sleep our kids were, lets just say…not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Jeremy and I went in and out of sleep - the out parts dominated by beseeching our children to “close their eyes!” and “stay on your own side of the bed!” - Ingrid led the nocturnal life with what appears at first glance to be two outfit changes, a dance party in the bed, at least a slice of pizza and some experimenting with the bidet.  Once she finally fell asleep, Noah was up and, after watching some Scooby Doo found a french language show about gem stones and diamonds followed by what I think was a Korean show about whale sharks?? Language barrier be damned!  We finally dozed off to some classical music led by a conductor with mime-level facial expressions. And while they are asleep at last, and while I am also mourning the loss of our “breakfast included” I am also looking forward to getting out and exploring what I am sure behind the blackout curtains is a beautiful place with these 1/2 zombie children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/13/day-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/13/day-1.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Santa Barbara</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/santabarbara/wharf.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
Santa Barbara is a pretty magical place.  Not like unicorn magical but magical because I’m not sure there is one word that can accurately describe it - so I went with magical.  When you mention Santa Barbara to people you almost always get back a happy sigh or that look on the face that happens when you reminisce about a place that made you feel different than other places do.  Not because of who you were with or what you did necessarily, but the energy that place infused you with.  So in that sense, it is magical.  BOOM!  There are so many things - natural beauty, cultures, restaurants, wine bars, people and parades.  There is a lot to love.  What we love the most however, are our friends, our old neighborhood and all the places we used to go and things we used to do when we lived there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was heartbreaking to leave and every time we visit we are reminded of why it was so heartbreaking.  Our little family basically lived out it’s toddler and little kid years there - filled with tantrums, power struggles and experimentations with fashion.  Santa Barbara mirrored, in many ways, those toddler years we were there - quirky and raw, yet authentic and beautiful.  We developed organic friendships - made amazing life-long friends - both our kids and ourselves. While at times it felt like we were just avoiding tearing the band-aid off with our visits up there after we moved, it would have been even more painful to not stay in touch with everyone and lose that feeling one gets about Santa Barbara that is so difficult to describe.  It does feel like a bubble - but it is a super-happy-irridecent-magical-unicorn bubble. And I hope that never changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/02/santa-barbara.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/02/santa-barbara.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intro</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/intro.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
It was a really challenging (first world challenging) year for our family.  After living in Santa Barbara and building a life there on our own we made the very difficult decision to leave and move back to our home town of Newport Beach (I said it was a first world type of challenging).  The decision came on the heels of what can only be described as a complete shit storm of family “happenings”.  Sometimes it felt like I was watching one of those independent films that, while you appreciate the gut wrenching performances of say, Michelle Williams or Ryan Gosling, or the artistic vision of Lars Von Trier, you’d prefer to keep the drama on the silver screen.  Changes at work, deaths, divorces, and, I shit you not, a fire.  Had it started raining frogs a year and a half ago I surely would have gone for the pint of Ben and Jerry’s in the freezer and high tailed it to the bunker.  It was just dramz to the max.  And we hate the dramz.  And the dramz back at home coincided with our kids totally finding their groove in Santa Barbara and making what we can only hope will be life - long buddies.  It was a groove that took a while too.  So to tear them away from that weighed really heavily on the heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we knew moving back and starting a new school would be hard for our kids.  We really underestimated the emotional toll it would take on all of us.  There were tears every day. Tantrums, fits of screaming, serious depression, and the kids were even worse.  But really, my mom has always said - “a mother is only as happy as her least happy child” and the deep wrinkles and under eye bags we both earned during this last year is a testament to that statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in this darkness, we learned a lot. As T-Swift so sagely says - “bandaids don’t fix bullet holes,”  kids can sagely smell bull-shit from a mile a way.  Sometimes you can’t make everything or even one thing better.  The only thing you can do is just sit and (I fucking hate that I am using this term) “hold space” for the pain and anguish that is being experienced.  Sometimes you sit your kid, or whoever and just be there for them.  Other times you leave them alone and let them feel and work through their pain on their own.  Pain, after all is the birthplace of empathy and empathy is you know, the all the rage right now.  Just ask Oprah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our kids have worked hard. And after a year, the happiness, laughter, silliness and shenanigans have returned, the dust is beginning to settle with the family and, as the “what-the-fuck-just-happened?” feeling starts to set in, we say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need a vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have A Rad Summer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 20:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/06/22/first-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/06/22/first-post.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
