<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Have a rad summer</title>
    <description>This is our travelblog Hope you like it
</description>
    <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.havearadsummer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 08:01:50 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 08:01:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting to Spain</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sansebastian/travel.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leonardo Da Vinci Airport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The security line at Rome Fiumicino felt a little like being backstage at the ballet dress rehearsals I used to go to when daughter was 3.  In spite of very detailed, almost by-the-minute- instruction with an undertone of shame if not followed, it really just ends up being a total shit show of shoes, bags, being one step ahead of a melt down, people talking with their hands a lot, and at completion, an inability to curtail your legs from power walking you to the nearest bar.  While I questioned whether some people had ever been in an airport security line, there were other people I was sure had just never been in any kind of line at all. With all the traveling we had done so far, this felt like a test of airport skill. Part logistical, part multitasking, with an element of Zen mastery – our kids proved again they were all stars. And then, like shoes in the airport security line, we were off.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/25/getting-to-spain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/25/getting-to-spain.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Melting in Rome</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rome/rome.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
It wasn’t just the heat - we were melting down in every sense of the word.  You could say we hit the traveling wall as soon as we got to Rome.  The Aperal Spritzer that had been flowing through my veins 24 hours earlier had been replaced by the fight or flight instinct that undoubtedly still figures largely in the collective mindset of this place - home to the gruesome gladiatorial battles of the Colosseum. So, cheers, I guess to the city for keeping it real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rome was intense. Beautiful, historic and amazing but intense.  Upon leaving the train station, I feared we had immediately fallen victim to what can only be described as one middle aged cab driver’s balls out audition for a Jason Bourne car chase stunt driver.  By the time we arrived, we were tired, hungry and frankly over pizza and pasta.  I personally was looking forward to changing into the shorts with the elasticated waisteband that had been advertised as both maternity and not.  Regardless there was a sizable gluten baby growing beneath my shirt so I figured I may as well be six months along. Contributing to the sense of “ick” was the fact that some of our clothes had taken on the scent of travel - a sort of stale air, slightly mildewy, body-odor potperie that would frankly, knock the Downy snuggle bear on its fluffy little arse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hit all the major sights - Pantheon, Colosseum, Forum, Trevi fountain.  We should have seen the tourists riding Segways into the sunset of the Colosseum as a sign of the coming apocalypse, but we ignored the signs and ended up with a melting 6 year old who’s list of complaints was only limited to here grasp of the english language.  After coming to grips with the fact that I had sold our ergo baby on craigslist about 5 years prior, it was time to saddle up and carry what was essentially a mass of child stuffed with pasta and butter with a glaze of sunscreen - making the grip all the more challenging.  For Noah however, walking amongst the ruins seemed to captivate him.  “What is that? How old is that? Can we go walk in there?”  Whether it was just his age or personal interests, it was fun to see that sense of awe in our child - for him to begin to see how truly large and old the world is.  These memories are what I hope will always give them perspective when they are feeling trapped in the bubble of home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, Rome was just as magestic and awe insipiring as we remembered even if it will be probably stand out as the most stressful part of the trip.  We were ripped off by cab drivers, and at restaurants and when it came time to leave it felt kinda like trying to stealthfully find your underwear in the dark after a one night stand or a sort or walk of shame.  Yet walk we did heads held high to the taxi stand and off to the airport.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/24/melting-in-rome.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/24/melting-in-rome.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Monsignor Della Casa</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tuscany/monsignordellacasa.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
Tuscany is slow but incredibly not boring.  We were worried 7 days in the Italian countryside would be a little much.  I worried about the kids wanting to be on their ipads the whole time and just bored to tears by the extraordinary rustic beauty and sense of peace we adults long to experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After renting a car in Pisa we hit the road for the 2-hour drive to Monsignor Della Casa  - a place we decided to stay after much research on the World Wide Web, aka, “the other woman.”  From the moment the tires of our Fiat Punto crunched down cathartically on the pea gravel of the driveway, I knew this place, with its sights, sounds (or lack thereof) and smells was the type that imprints itself fiercely upon you so that you are bombarded with happy memories at the faintest hit of rosemary, or sight of olive trees.  It was, to me, idyllic.  But I am rather sloth-like.  And with the rest of my family tends to have the energy of equal parts hummingbird and tween at a Justin Bieber concert. So we would have to see how this would go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After checking into our apartment we hit the pool, which, upon just first sight appeared to be a watering hole for the youth of the northern countries of the European union. We had picked this place because it looked like there would be lots of families and a chance for our kids to meet other kids.  It would just be a matter of cutting the cord.  Fortunately, Ingrid, after being stuck with her parents and no peers for the last week, hit the friend making trail with the persistence of a Jehovah Witness solicitor and the people skills of, well… Ingrid.
Watching kids make friends with other kids that speak very little of the same language is kind of like watching a baby being born.  I mean, you might support on the sidelines or worry that it’s not gonna happen but one way or the other that kid is comin’ out.  Or in this case, your kids will run off to the soccer field and play.  Because of the language barrier, Noah and Ingrid’s new friends from the Netherlands, were known as “the girl” and “the boy” for an embarrassingly long time.  But it didn’t seem to matter – they swam, played soccer, made bead necklaces and it all seemed to work.  While Ingrid was ready to slumber party at their apartment the first night, Noah was a little more reserved.  And in his defense it is hard to find motivation to make new friends when your dad is like the most fun dad in the world.  It’s a hard act to follow.  As has pretty much always been the case though, soccer is the equivalent of the mom who shows up to the park with a cooler full of those red, orange and purple popsicles on a 90-degree day.  It brings people together.  The soccer field was awesome. Close enough to the pool that they could hop out and play and hop in when it got too hot. That is where Noah really became buddies with the other kids and Jeremy logged in the majority of his fitbit steps for that leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It cracks me up to think that, prior to booking this place, we had a reservation for another that had a kitchen but no restaurant.  I thank my husband for realizing that this would not be as relaxing.  I’m sure he rightly imagined seven days of going to the market with me and the kids banging his head against the wall as I tried to wrestle my way through the analysis paralysis that is “what should we have for dinner tonight” in our house.   The food at the restaurant was amazing – people make reservations to eat there even when they are not guests.  The staff and servers know you and your children by name and remember what you like.  Complimenting this was the fact that we could put our kids order in for our kids and send them off to play with other kids and enjoy one of the aperol spritzers we had come to look forward to.  In addition to the great dinners, we also enjoyed having a cappuccino or two with fresh bread with butter and jam, eggs, croissants, ham and yoghurt for breakfast every morning – the Italian version of cocoa pebbles for the kids. You do whatcha gotta do folks. We did also make a couple trips to the Penny Market to get supplies for lunch along with some water bottles.  This is also where we got the random bead set that served as entertainment during parts of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it came time to leave, I was kind of emotional – the kind that feels a little over the top and embarrassing.  I tend to cry at people’s weddings that I am not particularly close to and then am totally dry eyed at the wedding of good friends. Kind of like that.  I can’t guarantee that we will be back there soon to visit, but am already looking forward to that rush of sensory flashback when we do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/23/monsignor-della-casa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/23/monsignor-della-casa.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cinque Terre</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/vernazza/vernazza.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
After crazy jet lag and the news of what happened in Nice, Vernazza was a place whose beauty almost seemed obnoxious and sarcastic.  Either that or we were just beyond turned in to the beauty of life after all the reports of horror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the birth of fricken Venus the kids emerged from their jet lagged shells to be their normal crazy-silly selves.  Obsessed with finding soccer jerseys and “rompers” in a city that is known more for its raw seaside feast of the senses than it’s consumerist delights the kids were a little horrified.  Their disappointment was short lived as we took to playing the very complicated game of throw-a-rock-and-get-it-to-stay-on-the-other-rock game.  Happiness all around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a much needed nights sleep we were up and ready to explore a different town.  We headed to Monterosso al Mare and upon arriving immediately regretted not coming fully prepared for a full beach day.  The beach was beautiful with beach chairs and typical Italian beach umbrellas, the water was clear and crisp and the views just beautiful.  Worth the 20 euros for two chairs.  Swimming out to rocks and laying in the sun made for a perfect beach day topped off with Gelato.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/15/cinque-terre.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/15/cinque-terre.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Post Nice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nice/nice2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
I hate when I catch myself thinking “we were just there” or essentially “it could have been us.”  We were walking on the same streets that a madman was doing recon on and would, a day later, massacre what is now 84 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate the implication of the statement that somehow we are special, because with situations like this it becomes pretty clear that death does not play by any rules.  Whether it is fate, karma, or luck, it seems pretty fricken awful to give the verbal equivalent of shrugging it off and moving on by saying something as stupid as “we were just there.”  Statements and feelings like this make me feel like I am excusing myself from fully empathizing with the victims, their families and the situation.  You can simultaneously feel the gravity the sadness and pain of something and still feel gratitude for your own safety.  If anything, sitting with those heavy feelings longer rather than trying to run from them brings you into the moment and then allows you to take in the precious and not so precious moments of life more fully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This trip has given us moments where the kids are angels and everything goes off without a hitch… these moments are easy to take in.  Then there are moments where they are freaking out, being brats, are hangry or something isn’t going as planned.  Our parenting sucks and we are sure we are forever scarring our children with our beautiful examples of passive agressive dialogue with each other. These are harder, but I try to see even these as a luxury and a piece of a larger puzzle that could be swept from the table at any moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/15/post-nice.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/15/post-nice.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day 3 - Italian train ride</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/vernazza/train.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
After a couple of intensely jet lagged days in nice, we took the party on the road…or the train as it were.  Somehow we pumped up the kids and got them ready to wake up at 08:30.  We went to bed at 12am and were up for a couple of hours of french TV - an opera about Cleopatra who’s costume captivated us all and ignited a is-it-her-real-boob-or-a transparent-fabric-with-painted-nipple debate.  Needless to say, with less than the recommended 8 hours of sleep, the next day wasn’t looking so good for us.  We tried not to think of the Britney circa 2007 style meltdowns leading to late arrivals that might await our day. But, to our surprise, the kids totally rallied and pulled off a marathon day of train travel with two exchanges, no lost luggage and a totally reasonable amount of tears.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/14/italian-train-ride.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/14/italian-train-ride.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day 1 - Nice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nice/nice.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
It’s a good thing people stay out late here cause we are sleeping right on through this day.  We arrived in Nice late last night and while Jeremy and I were ready to sleep our kids were, lets just say…not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Jeremy and I went in and out of sleep - the out parts dominated by beseeching our children to “close their eyes!” and “stay on your own side of the bed!” - Ingrid led the nocturnal life with what appears at first glance to be two outfit changes, a dance party in the bed, at least a slice of pizza and some experimenting with the bidet.  Once she finally fell asleep, Noah was up and, after watching some Scooby Doo found a french language show about gem stones and diamonds followed by what I think was a Korean show about whale sharks?? Language barrier be damned!  We finally dozed off to some classical music led by a conductor with mime-level facial expressions. And while they are asleep at last, and while I am also mourning the loss of our “breakfast included” I am also looking forward to getting out and exploring what I am sure behind the blackout curtains is a beautiful place with these 1/2 zombie children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/13/day-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/13/day-1.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Santa Barbara</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/santabarbara/wharf.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
Santa Barbara is a pretty magical place.  Not like unicorn magical but magical because I’m not sure there is one word that can accurately describe it - so I went with magical.  When you mention Santa Barbara to people you almost always get back a happy sigh or that look on the face that happens when you reminisce about a place that made you feel different than other places do.  Not because of who you were with or what you did necessarily, but the energy that place infused you with.  So in that sense, it is magical.  BOOM!  There are so many things - natural beauty, cultures, restaurants, wine bars, people and parades.  There is a lot to love.  What we love the most however, are our friends, our old neighborhood and all the places we used to go and things we used to do when we lived there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was heartbreaking to leave and every time we visit we are reminded of why it was so heartbreaking.  Our little family basically lived out it’s toddler and little kid years there - filled with tantrums, power struggles and experimentations with fashion.  Santa Barbara mirrored, in many ways, those toddler years we were there - quirky and raw, yet authentic and beautiful.  We developed organic friendships - made amazing life-long friends - both our kids and ourselves. While at times it felt like we were just avoiding tearing the band-aid off with our visits up there after we moved, it would have been even more painful to not stay in touch with everyone and lose that feeling one gets about Santa Barbara that is so difficult to describe.  It does feel like a bubble - but it is a super-happy-irridecent-magical-unicorn bubble. And I hope that never changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/dashboards/santabarbara.html&quot;&gt;Pictures / Videos / Stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/02/santa-barbara.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/07/02/santa-barbara.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intro</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/intro.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
It was a really challenging (first world challenging) year for our family.  After living in Santa Barbara and building a life there on our own we made the very difficult decision to leave and move back to our home town of Newport Beach (I said it was a first world type of challenging).  The decision came on the heels of what can only be described as a complete shit storm of family “happenings”.  Sometimes it felt like I was watching one of those independent films that, while you appreciate the gut wrenching performances of say, Michelle Williams or Ryan Gosling, or the artistic vision of Lars Von Trier, you’d prefer to keep the drama on the silver screen.  Changes at work, deaths, divorces, and, I shit you not, a fire.  Had it started raining frogs a year and a half ago I surely would have gone for the pint of Ben and Jerry’s in the freezer and high tailed it to the bunker.  It was just dramz to the max.  And we hate the dramz.  And the dramz back at home coincided with our kids totally finding their groove in Santa Barbara and making what we can only hope will be life - long buddies.  It was a groove that took a while too.  So to tear them away from that weighed really heavily on the heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we knew moving back and starting a new school would be hard for our kids.  We really underestimated the emotional toll it would take on all of us.  There were tears every day. Tantrums, fits of screaming, serious depression, and the kids were even worse.  But really, my mom has always said - “a mother is only as happy as her least happy child” and the deep wrinkles and under eye bags we both earned during this last year is a testament to that statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in this darkness, we learned a lot. As T-Swift so sagely says - “bandaids don’t fix bullet holes,”  kids can sagely smell bull-shit from a mile a way.  Sometimes you can’t make everything or even one thing better.  The only thing you can do is just sit and (I fucking hate that I am using this term) “hold space” for the pain and anguish that is being experienced.  Sometimes you sit your kid, or whoever and just be there for them.  Other times you leave them alone and let them feel and work through their pain on their own.  Pain, after all is the birthplace of empathy and empathy is you know, the all the rage right now.  Just ask Oprah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our kids have worked hard. And after a year, the happiness, laughter, silliness and shenanigans have returned, the dust is beginning to settle with the family and, as the “what-the-fuck-just-happened?” feeling starts to set in, we say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need a vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have A Rad Summer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 11:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/06/22/first-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.havearadsummer.com/2016/06/22/first-post.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
